

Alfeo Raymond

(+255) 745 909 129 (+255) 737 539 892 Ngelime07@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/pheogrammer/

Summary

I am an experienced software developer skilled in Web & Mobile Applications and Systems Development, APIs and Systems Integration, Automation with CI/CD practices, Database administration and Servers Configurations & Management, Technical Documentation, and IT Technical Training, Support & Consultation.

Working Experience

September 2019 - Present

University of Dar es salaam, CoICT - Software Developer (Contract)

- Design, Development, Testing and Maintenance of Systems.
- Integration of APIs and Subsystems.
- Configurations and Management of System Servers.
- Training users on how to use developed systems.
- Preparation and Writing of systems technical documents.
- Providing Technical Support to users.

April 2022 - Present

Tanzania Data Lab - *Technical Facilitator* (#CodeLikeAGirl)

- Train students about HCD
- Train students on how to translate ideas into code
- Train students about current technologies that they can use in ideas implementation
- Train students in the design and development of their ideas into apps
- Train students on competing with others to find the best app idea
- Train students on how to prepare presentations

July 2019 - Present

SmartGirlz in ICT Capacity Building Programme - *Coordinator*

- Planning, implementing, coordinating and evaluating all training operations.
- Facilitate technical training for ongoing programmes:
 - SmartGirlz in ICT Capacity Building Programme (July 2019- April 2022)

- Train students about HCD
- Facilitate students on how to translate ideas into code
- Facilitate students on the design and development of their ideas into apps
- Facilitate students on competing with others to find the best app idea
- o Globe Programme (October 2020 April 2021)
 - Train students on how to collect geographical data
 - Facilitate students on how to organize and process collected data
- dLab ICT & Entrepreneurship Capacity Building Programme (September 2021)
 - Train students on how to build a business out of problems they have discovered
 - Facilitate students on how to transform a business idea, into an actual product
 - Train business canvas model techniques and business sustainability techniques

March 2018 - December 2021

Freelance - Freelance Software Developer & Consultant

- Designing, Development, and Support of websites & Systems for clients
- Performing CI & CD for client's projects
- Technical support & Consultation
- Computer Maintenance

Volunteering Experience

October 2021 - Present

GitHub Education - GitHub Campus Expert

- I am a community leader who strives to build diverse and inclusive spaces to learn skills, share their experiences, and build projects together.
- leading in-person and online conferences, meetups, and hackathons, and maintaining open source projects.
- leading a community of students who dream of utilizing their technical skills and potential to the fullest and engaging in group activities and projects.

Education

November 2020 - July 2013

College of Business Education - Bachelor in Information Technology

November 2017 - July 2019

University of Dar es salaam, CoICT - Diploma in Computer Science

September 2016 - May 2017

College of Business Education, DSM - Certificate in Information Technology

January 2012 - November 2015

Iyunga Technical Secondary School, Mbeya - Certificate of Secondary Education

Computer Knowledge & Other Skills

Computer languages: HTML, XML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, Java, NodeJS, Python, C++

Computer Frameworks and CMSs: Laravel, Yii, Django, Joomla, Drupal, WordPress.

Computer programs & packages: Tally ERP, Oracle DB, PhpMyadmin, Docker, Git.

Operating systems: Windows, Linux, macOS.

Other Skills;

Computer Maintenance, Computer Networking, Search Engine Optimization, Data Entry, IT Technical Support, Social Media Management, Digital Marketing.

Languages

English

Writing: Fluently
Speaking: Proficient

Swahili

Writing: Fluently Speaking: Proficient

Honours and awards

- Techgig code gladiators 2021, TechGig India
- Best facilities mapper, dLab mapathon 2021, Tanzania Data Lab
- Android Developer, Google digital skills for Africa 2021, Andela

Organizations

- GitHub Campus Expert GitHub Education
- Member GDG Dar es salaam
- Member Africa Open Science & Hardware

Referees

- 1. Mr Fredrick Ishengoma (Projects Administrator, UDSM CoICT)
 - +255 754 623 457, fredishengoma@gmail.com
- 2. Madam Somoe Mkwachu (Trainings Coordinator, Tanzania Data Lab)
 - +255784 380 869 ,somoemkwachu@gmail.com
- 3. Mr Oscar Mashauri (Senior Systems Administrator, UDSM-CoICT)
 - +255754 677 873, oscar.mashauri@udsm.ac.tz